[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "Which of these is not one of the five functions of an operating system?",
    "options": [
      "Monitors system health and functionality",
      "Provides an environment for software to function",
      "Coordinates the activities of hardware components",
      "Sends and receives e-mail messages"
    ],
    "correct": "Sends and receives e-mail messages"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "CTRL-V is an example of what?",
    "options": [
      "Hotkeys",
      "System keys",
      "Function keys",
      "Launch keys"
    ],
    "correct": "Hotkeys"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "Which key combination switches between open applications in Windows and Linux (Unity)?",
    "options": [
      "F1",
      "ALT-F4",
      "ALT-TAB",
      "WINDOWS-PRINT SCREEN"
    ],
    "correct": "ALT-TAB"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "A __________ is a pointer that refers to a file.",
    "options": [
      "Launcher",
      "Taskbar",
      "Shortcut",
      "GUI"
    ],
    "correct": "Shortcut"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "The Dock on a Mac is equivalent to what feature of a Windows 8.1 desktop?",
    "options": [
      "Start button",
      "Notification area",
      "Launcher",
      "Taskbar"
    ],
    "correct": "Taskbar"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "Which of these is an accessibility option for people who have limited mobility?",
    "options": [
      "Speech recognition",
      "High-contrast color scheme",
      "Magnifier",
      "Windows flashing or blinking when a sound is played"
    ],
    "correct": "Speech recognition"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "What feature in Windows 10 is equivalent to Finder in macOS?",
    "options": [
      "File Explorer",
      "Control Panel",
      "Start screen",
      "Start menu"
    ],
    "correct": "File Explorer"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "Which of these is an open source operating system?",
    "options": [
      "Windows",
      "Linux",
      "iOS",
      "macOS"
    ],
    "correct": "Linux"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "What is the defining feature of a commercial OS?",
    "options": [
      "Open source",
      "Free",
      "Not free",
      "Public domain"
    ],
    "correct": "Not free"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "section": "Operating Systems",
    "question": "Which OS configuration uses data labels to control resource access?",
    "options": [
      "Services",
      "Scheduled tasks",
      "Mandatory access control",
      "EULA"
    ],
    "correct": "Mandatory access control"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "Which of these is the flow of static electricity?",
    "options": [
      "EMI",
      "ESD",
      "AC",
      "DC"
    ],
    "correct": "ESD"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "Which of these is a type of Windows user account?",
    "options": [
      "Kid",
      "Standard",
      "Supervisor",
      "Normal"
    ],
    "correct": "Standard"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "What device can help correct power sags?",
    "options": [
      "Power supply",
      "Power strip",
      "Surge suppressor",
      "UPS"
    ],
    "correct": "UPS"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "Where in the Control Panel can you remove unwanted applications?",
    "options": [
      "Programs",
      "Ergonomics",
      "Setup",
      "Start menu"
    ],
    "correct": "Programs"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "How far should a user's face be from a monitor screen for most comfortable viewing?",
    "options": [
      "10 to 12 inches",
      "12 to 16 inches",
      "16 to 24 inches",
      "24 to 32 inches"
    ],
    "correct": "16 to 24 inches"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "Where in Windows can you access the configuration settings for hardware devices like mice and printers?",
    "options": [
      "File Explorer",
      "EMI",
      "Start menu",
      "Control Panel"
    ],
    "correct": "Control Panel"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "What should you install before you download and install additional software on a new PC?",
    "options": [
      "Security software",
      "Nothing",
      "Updates to other applications",
      "Drivers for hardware devices"
    ],
    "correct": "Security software"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "What component protects against occasional electrical spikes?",
    "options": [
      "Surge suppressor",
      "Motherboard",
      "Hard disk drive",
      "Printer"
    ],
    "correct": "Surge suppressor"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "What kind of cable is most often used to connect a PC to a broadband modem or router?",
    "options": [
      "VGA",
      "DVI",
      "Ethernet",
      "RJ-11"
    ],
    "correct": "Ethernet"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "section": "Hardware",
    "question": "In which environment would a desktop computer be safest and operate the best?",
    "options": [
      "Inside a small, tightly sealed cabinet",
      "In a clean room with a powerful air conditioner running",
      "On the balcony at a tropical beachfront condo",
      "On a TV tray in a living room"
    ],
    "correct": "In a clean room with a powerful air conditioner running"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "Which of these passcodes is more secure?",
    "options": [
      "Six-digit alphanumeric",
      "Six-digit number",
      "Four-digit number",
      "All are equally secure"
    ],
    "correct": "Six-digit alphanumeric"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "The name of a WiFi access point is its:",
    "options": [
      "POP",
      "IMAP",
      "NFC",
      "SSID"
    ],
    "correct": "SSID"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "What kind of wireless connectivity is Bluetooth best suited for?",
    "options": [
      "Sending and receiving phone calls",
      "Connecting to a wireless headset",
      "Connecting to the Internet",
      "Connecting to a computer in a nearby building"
    ],
    "correct": "Connecting to a wireless headset"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "What app does an iPhone use to synchronize music and videos from a computer?",
    "options": [
      "iMusic",
      "iTunes",
      "Google Play",
      "doubleTwist"
    ],
    "correct": "iTunes"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "3G, 4G, and LTE are all kinds of what kind of wireless communication?",
    "options": [
      "WiFi",
      "Bluetooth",
      "Cellular",
      "NFC"
    ],
    "correct": "Cellular"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "How is screen orientation determined, if it is not locked?",
    "options": [
      "The user sets it once, and it never changes",
      "Orientation hardware button",
      "Orientation command",
      "Physical orientation of the device"
    ],
    "correct": "Physical orientation of the device"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "What is the gesture where you touch the surface with two fingers spread apart and then drag them closer together?",
    "options": [
      "Rotate",
      "Tap",
      "Pinch",
      "Spread"
    ],
    "correct": "Pinch"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "Connecting a Bluetooth peripheral to a smartphone is known as:",
    "options": [
      "Pairing",
      "WiFi",
      "4G",
      "NFC"
    ],
    "correct": "Pairing"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "Which of these terms is not associated with kinetics?",
    "options": [
      "Magnetometer",
      "Gyroscope",
      "Barometer",
      "Accelerometer"
    ],
    "correct": "Barometer"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "section": "Mobile Devices",
    "question": "Which of these is not a protocol for sending or receiving e-mail?",
    "options": [
      "IMAP",
      "SMTP",
      "POP3",
      "NFC"
    ],
    "correct": "NFC"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "section": "File Management",
    "question": "CTRL-V is a keyboard shortcut in Windows for what activity?",
    "options": [
      "Copy",
      "Paste",
      "Cut",
      "Delete"
    ],
    "correct": "Paste"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "section": "File Management",
    "question": "How do you select multiple noncontiguous files in a file listing?",
    "options": [
      "CTRL-click",
      "SHIFT-click",
      "Double-click",
      "Right-click"
    ],
    "correct": "CTRL-click"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "section": "File Management",
    "question": "What action opens a data file for editing in the application associated with its extension?",
    "options": [
      "Double-click",
      "Right-click",
      "CTRL-click",
      "SHIFT-click"
    ],
    "correct": "Double-click"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "section": "File Management",
    "question": "In File Explorer, from which tab can you select a different view?",
    "options": [
      "View",
      "Share",
      "Details",
      "Home"
    ],
    "correct": "View"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "section": "File Management",
    "question": "Which of these is an on/off flag for a file?",
    "options": [
      "Size",
      "Archive",
      "Date modified",
      "Date created"
    ],
    "correct": "Archive"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "section": "File Management",
    "question": "What is a root directory?",
    "options": [
      "The top-level storage location on a volume",
      "The folder containing the system files",
      "The folder containing the boot files",
      "The folder containing the signed-in user's personal files"
    ],
    "correct": "The top-level storage location on a volume"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "section": "File Management",
    "question": "What is the file management tool in macOS?",
    "options": [
      "File Explorer",
      "Dock",
      "Launcher",
      "Finder"
    ],
    "correct": "Finder"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "section": "File Management",
    "question": "Which utility in macOS backs up user files automatically?",
    "options": [
      "Backup",
      "File Explorer",
      "File History",
      "Time Machine"
    ],
    "correct": "Time Machine"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "section": "File Management",
    "question": "Which file property makes a search faster for content within files?",
    "options": [
      "Archive",
      "Indexed",
      "Compressed",
      "Encrypted"
    ],
    "correct": "Indexed"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "Which of these is a collaboration application?",
    "options": [
      "TurboTax",
      "Microsoft Word",
      "SharePoint",
      "Symantec Endpoint Protection"
    ],
    "correct": "SharePoint"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "What is the purpose of an application patch?",
    "options": [
      "Adding new features",
      "Removing the application",
      "Upgrading to a new version",
      "Correcting a problem"
    ],
    "correct": "Correcting a problem"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "How do you install a Modern app in Windows 8.1 or 10?",
    "options": [
      "From the Control Panel",
      "From a downloaded executable file",
      "From the Store app",
      "From the Start menu/screen"
    ],
    "correct": "From the Store app"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "Which of these is a productivity application?",
    "options": [
      "Microsoft Excel",
      "Candy Crush",
      "Windows Firewall",
      "Spotify"
    ],
    "correct": "Microsoft Excel"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "Where can you see what applications are installed in Ubuntu Linux?",
    "options": [
      "Apps list",
      "Dash pane",
      "Dock",
      "Windows Store"
    ],
    "correct": "Dash pane"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "What can you find out about an application by choosing Help | About?",
    "options": [
      "Most recent data file used",
      "Supported extensions",
      "Application version number",
      "Windows version"
    ],
    "correct": "Application version number"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "Where in Windows 8.1 can you browse installed applications?",
    "options": [
      "Apps list",
      "Dash pane",
      "Dock",
      "Windows Store"
    ],
    "correct": "Apps list"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "Which of these is a graphic format?",
    "options": [
      "PNG",
      "PPTX",
      "AVI",
      "TAR"
    ],
    "correct": "PNG"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "Which of these is a compression format?",
    "options": [
      "WAV",
      "TXT",
      "XLS",
      "RAR"
    ],
    "correct": "RAR"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "section": "Applications",
    "question": "How can you remove a Windows desktop application?",
    "options": [
      "From the Control Panel",
      "From the Store app",
      "From the Start menu/Start screen",
      "From the Dock"
    ],
    "correct": "From the Control Panel"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "section": "Networking",
    "question": "Which wireless encryption standard is the most secure?",
    "options": [
      "WPA",
      "WEP",
      "WPA2",
      "WPS"
    ],
    "correct": "WPA2"
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "section": "Networking",
    "question": "What kind of ports are on the back of a SOHO router for making wired connections?",
    "options": [
      "RJ-11",
      "DVI",
      "RJ-45",
      "VGA"
    ],
    "correct": "RJ-45"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "section": "Networking",
    "question": "Where in the Control Panel would you go to connect to a network printer on a client PC?",
    "options": [
      "Network and Internet",
      "System and Security",
      "Ease of Access",
      "Devices and Printers"
    ],
    "correct": "Devices and Printers"
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "section": "Networking",
    "question": "What differentiates a router from a switch?",
    "options": [
      "Routers are for WANs, and switches are for LANs",
      "A switch provides a path out of the LAN, such as to the Internet",
      "A router provides a path out of the LAN, such as to the Internet",
      "Routers are for client-server networks, and switches are for peer-to-peer networks"
    ],
    "correct": "A router provides a path out of the LAN, such as to the Internet"
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "section": "Networking",
    "question": "When shopping for a SOHO router, look for the latest available standard, which is:",
    "options": [
      "802.11b",
      "802.11ac",
      "802.11g",
      "802.11n"
    ],
    "correct": "802.11ac"
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "section": "Networking",
    "question": "How do you access a router configuration utility?",
    "options": [
      "Buttons on the back of the router",
      "Buttons on the top of the router",
      "Domain name in a web browser",
      "IP address in a web browser"
    ],
    "correct": "IP address in a web browser"
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "section": "Networking",
    "question": "What is an advantage of using a homegroup?",
    "options": [
      "Higher security level",
      "Easier folder and printer sharing",
      "Faster file transfer",
      "Makes router use less power"
    ],
    "correct": "Easier folder and printer sharing"
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "section": "Networking",
    "question": "In which way is a cellular Internet connection superior to wired and WiFi?",
    "options": [
      "Bandwidth",
      "Mobility",
      "Security",
      "Number of concurrent connections"
    ],
    "correct": "Mobility"
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "section": "Networking",
    "question": "What is the router's SSID?",
    "options": [
      "IP address",
      "Network name",
      "Serial number",
      "Model number"
    ],
    "correct": "Network name"
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "section": "Security",
    "question": "Which of the following can prevent people from snooping on a device that you leave unattended for several minutes?",
    "options": [
      "Shoulder surfing",
      "Disabling WiFi",
      "Using a strong password",
      "Configuring a lock-out time"
    ],
    "correct": "Configuring a lock-out time"
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "section": "Security",
    "question": "What indicates that you've browsed to a secure web page?",
    "options": [
      "The web address starts with http://",
      "A small key appears in the browser",
      "The web address starts with https://",
      "A small lock appears in the browser"
    ],
    "correct": "The web address starts with https://"
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "section": "Security",
    "question": "Which of the following might you want to disable to protect your privacy?",
    "options": [
      "Autofill forms",
      "Certificates",
      "InPrivate browsing",
      "Hyperlinks"
    ],
    "correct": "Autofill forms"
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "section": "Security",
    "question": "Which type of malware tries to get you to pay a fee to decrypt your files?",
    "options": [
      "Ransomware",
      "Trojan",
      "Spyware",
      "Worm"
    ],
    "correct": "Ransomware"
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "section": "Security",
    "question": "After you have recognized that there is a virus on your PC, what is the next step to removing the virus?",
    "options": [
      "To search and destroy",
      "To quarantine",
      "To educate",
      "To remediate"
    ],
    "correct": "To quarantine"
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "section": "Security",
    "question": "How can you defend against malware delivered by e-mail?",
    "options": [
      "Only use Mozilla Thunderbird",
      "Don't open attachments from unknown senders",
      "Delete old messages regularly",
      "Only use the preview window"
    ],
    "correct": "Don't open attachments from unknown senders"
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "section": "Security",
    "question": "What kind of theft does someone practice when they loiter at a café taking notes on what people type?",
    "options": [
      "Infiltration",
      "Shoulder surfing",
      "Cracking",
      "Dumpster diving"
    ],
    "correct": "Shoulder surfing"
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "section": "Security",
    "question": "Disabling the Bluetooth adapter on a laptop when it is not in use is an example of:",
    "options": [
      "Device hardening",
      "Hardware theft prevention",
      "Dumpster diving",
      "Cracking"
    ],
    "correct": "Device hardening"
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "What can you use to prevent ESD from damaging components when cleaning inside a computer?",
    "options": [
      "Antistatic wipe",
      "Antistatic bag",
      "ESD presents no danger to components, so nothing special is needed",
      "Antistatic wrist strap"
    ],
    "correct": "Antistatic wrist strap"
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "What should you use to remove dust and animal hair from inside a computer case?",
    "options": [
      "Compressed air",
      "Household vacuum cleaner",
      "Mild soap and water",
      "Blow dryer"
    ],
    "correct": "Compressed air"
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "What computer component contains a lot of lead and must be recycled?",
    "options": [
      "Toner cartridge",
      "CRT",
      "Ink cartridge",
      "Hard disk drive"
    ],
    "correct": "CRT"
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "What problem can missing slot covers on the case cause?",
    "options": [
      "Electromagnetic interference from other electronics nearby",
      "Disruption of airflow outside the computer leading to overheating",
      "Electrostatic discharge from dust and animal hair",
      "Disruption of airflow inside the computer leading to overheating"
    ],
    "correct": "Disruption of airflow inside the computer leading to overheating"
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "What standard offers computer part makers guidelines for making environmentally friendly parts?",
    "options": [
      "VHS",
      "FTC",
      "RIAA",
      "RoHS"
    ],
    "correct": "RoHS"
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "How should you clean removable media, such as a DVD?",
    "options": [
      "Use a soft cloth and wipe with a circular movement",
      "Use a soft scrub brush and wipe left to right",
      "Use a soft cloth and wipe inside to outside with a straight movement",
      "Put the disc in the dishwashing machine"
    ],
    "correct": "Use a soft cloth and wipe inside to outside with a straight movement"
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "How should you clean a computer that used to live in a machine shop?",
    "options": [
      "A soft cloth with a commercial cleaning solution",
      "A soft cloth with mild soap and water",
      "A soft cloth with distilled water",
      "A dry, soft cloth"
    ],
    "correct": "A soft cloth with mild soap and water"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "Which type of contingency plan is specific to an IT system or service?",
    "options": [
      "Incident response",
      "Disaster recovery",
      "Business continuity",
      "Data restoration"
    ],
    "correct": "Disaster recovery"
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "How long can a laptop remain in Hibernate mode without running out of battery power?",
    "options": [
      "It depends on the battery condition and capacity",
      "36 hours",
      "Indefinitely",
      "12 hours"
    ],
    "correct": "Indefinitely"
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "In California, how should small alkaline batteries be disposed of?",
    "options": [
      "Regular trash",
      "Any of the above",
      "Incinerated",
      "Recycling center"
    ],
    "correct": "Regular trash"
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "section": "Maintenance",
    "question": "In Sleep mode, the __________ remains powered; everything else shuts off.",
    "options": [
      "CPU",
      "Monitor",
      "Memory",
      "Hard drives"
    ],
    "correct": "Memory"
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "section": "Troubleshooting",
    "question": "What is the FAQ?",
    "options": [
      "The main page of a manufacturer's support web site",
      "A web page containing frequently asked questions and their answers",
      "A utility that identifies your product's model number",
      "An index of all help topics on a web site"
    ],
    "correct": "A web page containing frequently asked questions and their answers"
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "section": "Troubleshooting",
    "question": "Which is the most authoritative source of information about a device?",
    "options": [
      "Internet search",
      "Friend and relatives",
      "Manufacturer's web site",
      "Community user groups"
    ],
    "correct": "Manufacturer's web site"
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "section": "Troubleshooting",
    "question": "What should you try if a USB printer can print a test page but the computer doesn't see it?",
    "options": [
      "Use a different printer cable",
      "Replace the ink cartridges",
      "Turn the printer off and then back on again",
      "Use a different kind of paper in the printer"
    ],
    "correct": "Use a different printer cable"
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "section": "Troubleshooting",
    "question": "What Windows utility returns the computer's system files to previously saved versions?",
    "options": [
      "File Explorer",
      "System Restore",
      "Compatibility Mode",
      "Control Panel"
    ],
    "correct": "System Restore"
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "section": "Troubleshooting",
    "question": "Which of these might correct a problem with an application not running correctly?",
    "options": [
      "Clean the display screen",
      "Uninstall and reinstall the application",
      "Create a shortcut to the application on the desktop",
      "Delete your data files"
    ],
    "correct": "Uninstall and reinstall the application"
  },

  {
    "id": 83,
    "section": "Troubleshooting",
    "question": "Suppose you have a wireless mouse that doesn't work at all. Which of these is not likely to be the cause?",
    "options": [
    "The power switch on the mouse is turned off",
    "The mouse is dirty",
    "The batteries are dead",
    "The transceiver is not connected to the computer"
    ],
    "correct": "The mouse is dirty"
    },
    {
    "id": 84,
    "section": "Troubleshooting",
    "question": "If you need to cancel an online subscription, what department of the company do you need to contact?",
    "options": [
    "Customer service",
    "Technical support",
    "Service",
    "Sales"
    ],
    "correct": "Customer service"
    },
    {
    "id": 85,
    "section": "Troubleshooting",
    "question": "Which of these could not be the cause of a computer appearing completely dead?",
    "options": [
    "Bad keyboard",
    "Hibernate mode",
    "Disconnected power cable",
    "Bad power cable"
    ],
    "correct": "Bad keyboard"
    }
]